Hello everyone and welcome to
English Pod, my name is Marco.
And my name is Catherine and
today we're talking about money issues.
That's right.
So there are some
really interesting phrases
and we're going to
learn a little bit about
how money and social security
works in the United States.
But before we get into that, why
don't we look at vocabulary preview?
Very cabaret-y preview.
So we're talking about retirement
and that means we're going
to talk about when you stop
working when you're 63 or 65.
How do you save money for that?
And the phrase we've
got here is retirement plan.
All right.
So a retirement plan.
So as you say, that's
some money that you
have for when you retire when you're
65, when you're too old, maybe to work.
Exactly.
And there are many different kinds.
We're going to hear about
one that's called a 401k.
But we'll talk about that in a minute.
First, let's listen to today's dialogue.
Well, that was an interesting documentary.
For sure.
I didn't really
understand some of the
technical jargon they
used in the film when
they talked about
social security in the US.
And like what?
Well, they mentioned how people put
away money in something called a 401k.
Yeah, I know it sounds
weird, but a 401k is a
type of retirement plan
that allows employees
to save and invest for
their own retirement.
Everyone tries to
contribute as much as
possible so that when you retire, you
can rest peacefully on your nest egg.
That's interesting and logical, I guess.
In my country, we also have to contribute
to a government-run retirement fund.
But most people
don't really trust it, so
they just invest in
properties or things like that.
That seems a bit unstable, don't you think?
Yeah, but corrupt
governments in the past have
created distrust among
banks and financial institutions.
So, no, people prefer to have
money hidden in a jar or a piggy bank.
I've been thinking of doing that lately.
I don't want some banker
to run off with my money.
All right, we're back
from today's dialogue now.
Some really interesting
words and phrases there.
And as you said, this 401k, what is a 401k?
Well, I'm not sure about
the details honestly,
but the 401k plan
is a plan for workers,
people who are young and
working, to invest in their retirement.
And so it's a way to save money.
So every day, they
put a little bit of money
towards this plan, and
in the end, when they
retire, they will have
a certain amount of
money that they can use
throughout their senior hood.
Exactly.
And so, before we
have that, we have this
conversation, which
starts with a documentary.
So they're learning about 401ks.
And in this case, the
person says that they didn't
understand a lot because there
was a lot of technical jargon.
All right, so this word jargon,
jargon, it's very similar to slang, right?
Exactly.
And it's a special kind
of talking or special
words related to a certain
topic, or a certain industry.
For example, you hear a
lot of business jargon, right?
Or marketing jargon?
Yeah.
When people start
talking about, you know,
POPs and POS and like
all that jargon is doing.
Sorry.
I don't get that.
Well, jargon then is special
language for a certain industry or field.
And in this case, we're learning about
financial jargon and investment jargon.
So we're talking about 401ks
and funds and all that stuff.
So, okay, very good.
And now, when they
were talking about the
401k, he explained how they
deduct money to put into this plan.
Well, the question is, who deducts
money and where does it all go?
And so to deduct means
to take away, and this
means in a 401k plan, the government will
deduct money from your paycheck and put it
into a special savings plan for you
that you can access when you're retired.
Okay.
So, to deduct means to
take away, to take out, right?
Exactly.
So, subtract the duct, take away, take out.
Very good.
All right.
And as they kept talking
about money issues,
the women said that people in our country
distrust banks and financial institutions.
Okay.
So, you might recognize a
word there, distrust, trust.
They have the same root.
And so, to trust someone is to believe
in them and to believe what they say.
But to distrust means to
think what they're saying is a lie.
Okay.
So, you don't really believe that person.
No.
So, if someone says, trust me, I will
take your money and I won't spend it.
You say, "Mm, I
distrust this person.
" I mean, I don't trust.
Right.
Very good.
And well, why do they
distrust these institutions
because the government
is a bit corrupt.
Okay.
So, you hear this word a lot in
the news or in the newspaper.
You can have a corrupt
government or a corrupt politician.
That means that the government does things
but says it doesn't and maybe is dishonest.
It's distrustful.
Right.
So, for example, a
corrupt politician will
support a law that's not really good, but
maybe he's being paid by somebody else.
Or a corrupt politician
will take money from
the government institutions to use for
himself and not for the country or the people.
That's right.
But, uh, corrupt government then.
Okay.
Very good.
All right.
So, why don't we listen
to our dialogue again
and we'll be back soon
with Fluency Builder.
Well, that was an interesting documentary.
For sure.
I didn't really
understand some of the
technical jargon they
used in the film when
they talked about
Social Security in the US.
And like what?
Well, they mentioned how people put
away money in something called a 401k.
Yeah.
I know it sounds weird,
but a 401k is a type
of retirement plan
that allows employees
to save and invest for
their own retirement.
Through a 401k, you can
authorize your employer
to deduct a certain amount of money from
your paycheck, invest it in the 401k plan.
Everyone tries to
contribute as much as
possible so that when you retire, you
can rest peacefully on your nest egg.
That's interesting and logical, I guess.
In my country, we also
have to contribute to
a government-run
retirement fund, but most
people don't really trust it so they just
invest in properties or things like that.
That seems a bit unstable, don't you think?
Yeah.
But corrupt governments
in the past have created
distrust among banks
and financial institutions.
So now people prefer to have
money hidden in a jar or a piggy bank.
I've been thinking
of doing that lately, I
don't want some banker
to run off with my money.
All right, we're back so on fluency builder,
we're going to look at three phrases.
So let's look at them now.
Fluency builder.
Okay, this first phrase is what
the entire dialogue is about.
It's about putting away money.
So to put it away.
Okay, so to put money away,
that's an equivalent of saving, right?
Exactly.
To save.
So in this case, to put
away is a fixed phrase,
these words that go
together very often.
It means to save.
So you could say, "Oh yeah,
last year I put away $1,000.
" No, okay.
So you saved $1,000.
Exactly.
Very good.
And why are we putting all this money away?
We're trying to build a nest egg.
Now this is a funny phrase.
That is funny.
A nest is a home for a bird.
You know, it's made of
sticks and twigs and leaves.
Right.
And a nest egg then has to
do with a bird's eggs in the nest.
Well, I don't know where it
comes from, but it does mean
money that you've saved
up for some date in the future.
So you could say, "I'm
trying to grow a nest egg.
I'm trying to build a nest egg.
" So that in 10 years,
I can buy a house.
Okay.
So it's not only for retirement.
You can build a nest egg to possibly
invest it in the future and to buy a house.
Exactly.
You're savings that you don't touch.
So I could say, "I'm going to kill you.
You spent the nest egg.
" All right.
That's not for spending.
It's for saving.
All right.
And where can you save
money for your nest egg?
It's very popular to
put it in a piggy bank.
Well, maybe if you're
five years old, but I don't
know if I'd put a lot of
money in a piggy bank.
Piggy bank is usually
a ceramic pig, you
know, and it's got a hole in the
top and you can put coins in the top.
So we give these to
children to teach them how
to save, so they can put
one penny in every day.
And then when they
need the money or they
want to spend it, they
break the piggy bank.
Exactly.
You have to throw it
on the ground, and it's
sad because you realize, "Oh,
no, I don't have my piggy bank.
" Lost my nest egg.
All right.
So why don't we listen
to this dialogue again?
Let's keep a lookout for all these words
and phrases and we'll be back shortly.
Well, that was an interesting documentary.
For sure.
I didn't really
understand some of the
technical jargon they
used in the film when
they talked about
social security in the US.
And like what?
Well, they mentioned how people put
away money in something called a 401(k).
Yeah, I know it sounds
weird, but a 401(k) is
a type of retirement
plan that allows employees
to save and invest for
their own retirement.
Through a 401(k),
you can authorize your
employer to deduct a
certain amount of money from
your paycheck, invest
it in the 401(k) plan.
Everyone tries to contribute
as much as possible
so that when you retire, you can
rest peacefully on your nest egg.
That's interesting and logical, I guess.
In my country, we also
have to contribute to
a government-run
retirement fund, but most
people don't really trust it, so they just
invest in properties or things like that.
That seems a bit unstable, don't you think?
Yeah, but corrupt
governments in the past have
created distrust among
banks and financial
institutions, so no people prefer to have
money hidden in a jar or a piggy bank.
I've been thinking of doing that lately.
I don't want some banker
to run off with my money.
All right, we're back, so
this whole savings thing.
Are you good at saving?
Do you have your nest egg
planned out for your retirement?
Nest egg, no, but I'm a compulsive saver.
Really?
Like to save a lot.
Oh, wow.
Yeah.
Because you never know when you're going to
need money, and I think once you get a kind
of adult job, you know,
the nine to five job,
it's important to spend
as little as possible
so that you can create
an nest egg or some
kind of savings account
for the future, because
it'd be nice to have a
car or a house someday.
Right, right.
And also, as you say,
unexpected things happen,
so something may happen, maybe you break
your arm and you don't have any savings or
maybe no insurance,
so at least you have
some money stashed
away where you can use it.
Exactly.
And I know that in America
right now in the news,
the credit crisis is very
popular to talk about.
And so part of this economic situation is
that people owe more money than they have.
That means they've spent
more money than they own.
And so they don't have any savings.
And that really scares me.
So I think it's a really smart idea to
start investing as soon as you can.
Very good.
All right.
Why is financial advice
from EnglishPod.com?
Thank you.
All right.
So if you have any
questions, any doubts or
any more financial questions,
please come to EnglishPod.
com and we'll
see you guys there.
Bye, everyone.
Bye.